# GIUSEPPE IACONO

# New York, NY **Python Developer**

alchemist.bounty@protonmail.com · <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/giuseppe-iacono-441805224/">https://github.com/alchemist-bounty</a> · <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/alchemist\_bounty">https://www.hackerrank.com/alchemist\_bounty</a>

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

# **SKILLS**

- Fully worked with Django and Flask
- Managed AirFlow Projects
- Worked on Web Sites Scraping and Automation
- Managed Relational Databases Systems, NoSQL, Web development and Web services
- Managed and maintained development of PYTHON backend for dynamic database driven websites
- Provided technical support in the assurance of quality systems and system changes
- Proficient in CSS3/HTML5, JavaScript Libraries including jQuery, React, Vue, Angular, Ember and Backbone, Highcharts and D3
- Work with QUnit for Javascript Testing Framework
- AWS (Lambda, Elastic Search, S3, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, SNS, SQS)
- Google Cloud Platform (Composer, GCP AirFlow, Compute Engine, BigTable, BigQuery, Firebase)
- CI / CD (CircleCI, Travis, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Vercel)
- oAuth, Sentry

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER**

#### **ALGONAUT**

#### JUN 2022 - AUG 2022

- Work with React.js, Next.js with Cryptocurrency Trading Platform.
- Work with Typescript with React
- Use Jest testing framework and use of custom Component / Query / Hook in React
- Integration of HighChart, Performance improvement
- Deployment to Vercel with github integration
- Blockchain Development using PHP.

#### SENIOR BACKEND ENGINEER

# **LIGHTPONG**

#### DEC 2021 - JUN 2022

- Backend API development for Gaming console

- Work with Node.js, Express.js and Sequelize.js.
- Use Jest as testing framework and integrate oAuth
- Work with MySql and deployment to AWS
- Implement Middleware and nested routes
- Work with Auth0 as oAuth implementation

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

# **FREELANCER**

#### 2019 - 2021

- Working in various mid to big size projects to provide professional services for individuals and business clients. Provides full range of services, including development, testing, deploying and maintenance.
- Working as Full stack developer in Content Management, Sports, Online School, eCommerce, Management, Finance applications, Medical, Marketing, Auto Mobile, Real Time and Real Estate projects.
- Building applications based on PHP (Laravel, Symfony) and Python (Flask, Django) for Online School, Real Estate, Medical and Marketing projects.
- Building Ruby-based applications using Rails, Sinatra with testing features for Map-based, Internal Mangement Projects and Back end API.
- Building applications based on Microsoft .Net technologies including ASP.NET Core, Site Core for Sports and Customer Management projects.
- Building Java Based applications based on Struts, JSF and Spring for Enterprise level projects.
- Building Node.js-based applications using MEAN / MERN stack for Real Time data and CRM with Express and Sequelize.
- Building frontend application using various JavaScript frameworks (Angular, React, Vue, Next, Nuxt, D3 and Three.is).
- Blockchain Development (Bitcoin, Ethereum, Moralis, Web3).

# **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

# **MUMBA TECHNOLOGIES**

# 2016 - 2018

- Worked as Full stack developer in Content Management, Sports, Online School, eCommerce, Management, Finance applications, Medical, Marketing, Auto Mobile, Real Time and Real Estate projects.
- Built Ruby-based applications using Rails, Sinatra and Padrino with testing features for Sports, Signing, Crawling, Farming, VR Device Data Parsing, eCommerce and Content Management Projects.
- Built frontend application using various JavaScript frameworks (Angular, D3, Three, React, Vue, Leaflet and Lodash).
- Developed and customized the themes and plugins for eCommerce & CMS applications including WordPress, Joomla, Drupal, Shopify, Spree, BigCommerce and etc...
- Worked on Hosting server management like Amazon Server, Heroku, Godaddy, Bluehost and etc...

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### **EMLOGIS**

2013 - 2015

- Worked as Java Backend developer in Staff Scheduling Software (J2SE, J2EE, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, JFreeChart, Spring, EJB, TomCat).
- Built frontend application using various JavaScript frameworks (AngularJS, Angular, D3, Three, React, Backbone, Ember, Ext JS, Knockout, Leaflet and Lodash).
- Applied the database design with SQL functions and procedures.
- Built graph features using Php & Python library as well as Javascript Graph library.
- Built Node.js-based applications using MEAN / MERN stack for Real Time data and CRM.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# SYNERGY BUSINESS CONSULTING

# 2009 - 2012

- Worked as Backend and Frontend developer in various eCommerce, Management, Finance applications.
- Built applications based PHP (Codeigniter, Symfony, Yii, Cakephp), Python (Flask, web2py, Django).
- Built applications based on Microsoft .Net technologies including C#, VB.Net and SharePoint: ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Razor, ADO.NET and Entity Framework.
- Built Java Based applications using J2SE, J2EE and JSP based projects. (Struts, Hibernate, JFreeChart, Spring, EJB, TomCat).
- Built frontend application using various JavaScript frameworks (ExtJS, jQuery, Dojo, HighChart, Knockout).

# **EDUCATION**

# **PRIVATE EDUCATION COMPANIES**

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSE

2006 - 2009

# **TOURO COLLEGE**

# **BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN MATHMATICS**

1993 - 1997

# **PORTFOLIO**

https://imentor.org/ (Angular, Python/Flask)

http://salemenv.com/ (Flask, Php, React)

http://daybreaker.com/ (Django)

https://chipsroofingllc.com/ (Django)